My first day back in school

Day 00544: Thursday, 2016 September 01

Current countdowns:

20 unfinished weblog entries in July
18 days until mobile voice/SMS service with my current carrier ends
48 days until mobile data service with my current carrier ends
3-6 business days (5-10 days) until my ID card is supposed to arrive
45 days until my old domain registrar can no longer counter my charge dispute

I fully intended to start my coursework right away this morning, and in fact, I intended to start late last night. Last night though, I got exited putting together the tree/list of course dependencies, and that took too much time to finish. I think it was worth it, as I now have a pretty good idea of where I'm going, but it did get me off to a late start. This morning, I again put off going to class, but this time, I didn't have a legitimate excuse. I wanted to re-unify my website, allowing access to my weblog to clearnetters; the thought on this being that as I'm going to have to write journal entries that I submit for classes, and maybe I'd want to link to my regular journal within them at times. However, the reunification process was not at all quick, and took several hours. In all honesty, I should have waited until completing my coursework for the week, but I doubt that I would have been able to concentrate in my excitement. I've finished the merging process, though there still exists a lot that I need to do to clean up the website in general; things that I'd have needed to do with or without the merge. While merging, I tried to keep the optimizations made in both websites, as they'd been developed separately for a while, as well as remove all invalid instances of this website's domain name without a dot. That took a lot of hand editing, as I needed to make sure to fix/remove all instances of the domain in hyperlinks and comments, while maintaining the instances that were instead in readable text in the journal entries. Some of these instances in the entries were there mentioning the transition many months ago, while others were just instances of mentioning the domain before I understood that using the trailing dot was allowed. In either case, to preserve the integrity of the entries and what they meant at the time that they were written, their text needed to remain intact. I feared that the currently-missing journal entries in July might cause a couple dead hyperlinks to show up in the navigation, one on the page of the entry right before the gap and one on the page of the entry right after the gap, but surprisingly, everything worked out! Some of my source code for this website is a bit old, and I hardly ever look at it, so I forget the way that it actually functions sometimes. Speaking of dead links to missing weblog pages, I won't be linking to this weblog from the main navigation at all. This journal will be accessible, but semi-secret. If you know that it's here, you're welcome to read it, but it's not going to be broadcast everywhere like it once was.

After fixing up the website (mostly), I remembered that I had another thing on my to do list for the day. I needed to get my Cricket device unlocked in preparation for canceling my service through them! This time, that went rather smoothly, and hopefully this time, I won't be back. I really do prefer T-Mobile as a company.

Finally actually working on my schoolwork, I started with UNIV 1001. The readings for the week were kind of short, and I found that they had this to say about assignment submission file formats:

Unless otherwise specified, the format of your uploaded file must be one that can be opened by MS Office and Open Office programs. Please submit all your text work as .doc or .odt files.

For presentations, use .ppt or .odp files and for spreadsheets use .xls or .ods files. If you try to upload a file that is bigger than the maximum file upload size (10MB), you will receive an error message.

University of [REDACTED] accepts assignments in the standard LibreOffice/OpenOffice formats! I was happy just to be free to use free software to create documents to submit in the lame Microsoft formats, but it looks like I won't even need to worry about saving them that way. I took the quiz as well, though it was more of an open-book scavenger hunt across the university's website. The real point of it was to make sure that we know how to use their site to get the information that we need. I was going to work on the journal entry and discussion problem for the week as well, but they both looked pretty daunting. I got the feeling that they weren't really meant to be, but they asked questions that are more complex than most people probably realize. For example, part of the discussion question asked what the role of higher education institutions is today, as well as how their mission has changed in the past few decades. Personally, I think that these institutions used to be about generating and sharing knowledge, however, these days, they tend to try to hoard knowledge instead. They use students to figure out solutions to problems, then they patent said solutions so that the world can't have them. Often times, these patents are sold, either to patent trolls or to companies that want a monopoly on the ideas. Schools aren't what they used to be, and I'm going to need to find a bunch of sources to cite and back my point. I'm just not up for that today. Hopefully I'll get started on that tomorrow.

POLS 1503 had a lot more reading to get through, and unlike UNIV 1001's readings, many of these readings are available on websites open to the public instead of behind the school's login wall. You're welcome to read along with me, if you have the time and desire!

Films On Demand - View Playlist
What Is Globalization?
Terrorism May Have Put Sand In Its Gears But Globalization Won't Stop
multicolor728.qxd - beg_12.pdf
The Globalization Website - Debates
The Globalization Website - Theories
The Globalization Website - Theories
The Globalization Website - Theories
The Globalization Website - Theories
Culture | Globalization101
Development | Globalization101
Environment | Globalization101
Health | Globalization101
Investment | Globalization101
Technology | Globalization101
Trade | Globalization101
What Is Globalization? | Globalization101
What effect has globalization had on international investments? | Investopedia

In place of one of those was supposed to be a video, but I couldn't get the video working. As I was about to ask for advice from the class, I noticed that there was a link to a transcript, which was a better option than a video anyway. One of those links is also a working video; I couldn't find a transcript for it though. I use the term "working" loosely, as I was and still am having technical difficulties with it, but at least it partially plays. Eventually, I gave up on trying to watch it. Tomorrow, I should finish the above readings.

I received a letter from Discover stating that they have credited my account by the amount of the charge that I'm disputing. However, they say that my former domain registrar has forty-five days to counter my dispute, in which case, the money will once again leave my account. If that happens, I will once more need to contact Discover and ask them how to de-authorize the domain registrar from charging to my account. The registrar refused to disable automatic payments on my behalf and I no longer have my log in credentials to do it myself because of the incident.

Document modifications

On 2017-11-02, this journal page was modified in order to redact the name of the university.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.1 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Procrastination

Day 00545: Friday, 2016 September 02

Current countdowns:

20 unfinished weblog entries in July
17 days until mobile voice/SMS service with my current carrier ends
47 days until mobile data service with my current carrier ends
2-5 business days (4-9 days) until my ID card is supposed to arrive
44 days until my old domain registrar can no longer counter my charge dispute

Our mother and Vanessa went to Salem in search of a home and a school. If Vanessa isn't registered for school by today, they'll miss their first day! Unfortunately, the schools won't allow one to register unless they have a local address, so we need to at least know where we'll be living before registration.

dotMP sent me another notification about my expiring domain. It seems that I'm already down to thirty days before it expires. I'm not adding that to my new list of countdowns though, as it's not that big of a deal. I only bought that name accidentally and I never even found a use for it.

I really didn't want to work on the readings for POLS 1503 today. While globalization is a very important topic, reading about it is rather boring. I ended up putting it off for most of the day. I knew that in order to avoid falling behind though, I needed to complete the readings by the end of the day, so eventually, I did get to work. I checked back with the POLS 1503 classroom, and the discussion assignment still hasn't been posted! This doesn't bode well. For one thing, I wasn't able to see what I was supposed to be looking for in the readings, so when the discussion assignment is finally posted, I'm likely going to need to go back and reread a lot of this. I doubt that I have time for that at the moment, as my life is a bit in chaos at the moment. Also though, what if it doesn't get posted at all before the deadline? Will we still be marked down for not completing it? Or worse still, what if it's posted at the last minute and we're all supposed to notice it and rush to completion? I won't be able to do the best of jobs in that situation, plus we cannot complete the section involving replying to others until both we've posted our own answers and others have posted answers for us to reply to. The journal assignment has been posted though, and it requires both introducing ourselves and defining at least three words that we didn't know from the readings. I've located thirteen such words, so I'll define all of those and hope that it makes up for my slowness in other areas, such as even completing the readings.

Our mother had a few tasks for us while they were away. Cyrus was to clean the kitchen and locate whatever nasty smell my mother is smelling. I can't smell it, myself. My mother claims to have a bad nose, but their nose is actually pretty strong, whether they admit it or not. They're constantly complaining about smells that I can't even detect or are not very strong for me. In any case, Cyrus thinks that they might have found it, but it's not good news. It might be coming from the sink, in which case it could be sewer odor coming in through a cracked pipe. My tasks were to clean one of the restrooms and to clean up the pile of recyclables near the front door. Honestly, with how much I was procrastinating with my schoolwork, I should have had both done. However, I've only gathered the recyclables, and I'll finish with the restroom tomorrow. To get the recyclables out of the way, I walked down to a distant recycling dumpster. Cyrus needed a break, and came with me carrying our trash to the trash dumpster in the same parking lot.

Tomorrow, I need to show a bit more motivation. I need to get the restroom cleaned, complete at least one of the two journal assignments for the week, take the remaining quiz, and probably work on the discussion assignment that was posted in UNIV 1001, as that one's actually available.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

T-Mobile's scam

Day 00547: Sunday, 2016 September 04

Current countdowns:

20 unfinished weblog entries in July
15 days until mobile voice/SMS service with my current carrier ends
45 days until mobile data service with my current carrier ends
42 days until my old domain registrar can no longer counter my charge dispute

I'm trying to transition from a mobile plan with a telephone line attached to a mobile plan that is data-only. Quite frankly, I can't stand the telephone number system. In the past, telephone numbers were like IP addresses. They were simply machine-readable integers that helped the telephone network know where to route calls. This isn't very user friendly. Whould you want to type https://198.35.26.96/ to reach Wikipedia? No! How many people would even recognize Wikipedia's IP address if they saw it? Instead, here on the Internet, we have a little thing called DNS. It allows us to point human-readable and human-memorable names at these machine-readable numbers. This makes the Internet a much more user-friendly place! However, for some idiotic reason, people just accept the telephone number system. The only gripe that they seemed to have about it was that if one switched providers, they'd have to change what number was used to reach them. Expecting to keep your numeric address when you switch telephone providers is like expecting to keep your numeric IP address when you change Web server hosts or expecting to keep your postal address when you move! These numbers are addresses, not names. Again, back to domain names, when you switch Web or email hosts, you update your DNS records to point to your new address. This name/address system was eventually implemented in the telephone network, at least here in the United States. However, it was done in a horridly screwy way. Instead of making the names human-memorable, the names are all-numeric and match the old addressing scheme! Let's be clear here. Once, your telephone number used to be an address on the telephone network. However, it's now a name that needs to be looked up in a lookup table, similar to DNS, but without the benefit of human readability! Telephone numbers now lack both the efficiency of bare addresses and most of the benefits of lookup table names. This is exceedingly foolish. Even worse, everyone seems to expect everyone else to be okay not only being reached via these numbers, but especially *identifying* as these numbers. I want no part of that, and as such, much prefer email. I only even have a mobile telephone line because my network of choice, T-Mobile, doesn't offer service in Coos Bay. The only other GSM provider in this section of the globe is AT&T, and their more reasonable plans, which are offered under the Cricket name, all come with telephone lines. Now that I'm back where my favorite network actually covers, I'm going back to a data-only plan.

I'd heard about a deal at T-Mobile in which they will give you a gratis tablet. The catch is that you have to be on postpaid service to get it. You also have to stick around for two years. While T-Mobile won't call it a contract, the tablet is only gratis with this two-year agreement. Normally, I much prefer prepaid service. I've never even had a postpaid account because I find them to be noxious. However, their prepaid and postpaid tablet plans are the same price, so I decided to go in and ask them about it. T-Mobile has a no-credit-check option that would eliminate much of the pain of a postpaid account. There is no good reason for a carrier to have your Social Security number! I still prefer prepaid plans because they put the customer in control instead of the company, and I hate the idea of selling my freedom for two years. Still, the plan that comes with a tablet is the same price per month as the plan that doesn't, so it was tempting. There was also a lack of clarity that needed to be dealt with. Supposedly, current customers can get the tablet with the plan that I would want, but new customers are required to get a plan that costs 350% of the price of that plan. That's a little much! I needed more information. The first thing that I got cleared up was yes, the inexpensive plan does qualify new customers for the tablet, regardless of what the promotional material claimed. T-Mobile's been trying to push their new unlimited data plan, but it's much more expensive for those of us that use only slightly above one gigabyte of data each month. I'd heard that with the no-credit-check option, a down payment on service is required, so I next asked how much that would be. As it turns out, if you don't want to hand over your Social Security number, you don't qualify for the tablet offer. In other words, the tablet offer is only a scam to get your Social Security number! Shame, shame. I expected better of you, T-Mobile. This is likely a big part of why T-Mobile pushes for people to go postpaid instead of prepaid though.

Ronsor has disconnected their IRC server from Umbrellix, so I feared that I was going to lose contact with them again. It seems like they keep popping up, connecting their server to tiny networks that I'm on, then disconnecting and disappearing. Last time, they claimed that their server was operational, but I never could connect to it. This time, they said that their old onion address was up, but again, I couldn't reach their server. I asked them about it today, and they took a look and fixed the problem. Hopefully as Ronsor's nomadic piece of the Internet moves again, I won't once again lose my friend.

I've located the reason that I didn't notice the missing discussion assignment in POLS 1503 when I was reading through the week's work before. While the question set doesn't exist on the discussion board yet, the questions are present in the reading material. I can begin working on answering those questions tomorrow. However, because of the strange way in which the University of [REDACTED] discussion boards are set up, we students aren't able to speak in the discussion room until the professor formally asks the questions. In addition to writing up my answers to what it appears that the questions will be, I need to try again to contact the professor about the issue. This time, I will attempt a more direct approach. If I can find email addresses, I will try writing a letter. However, if the University of [REDACTED] interface isn't having issues, we seem to have ten professors in that course. I can't be sure if we legitimately have that many professors, and if not, which one(s) are the actual instructors of our class, as I haven't seen any trace of any of these people around the classroom. I will try to contact them all, and hopefully not be pestering people that have nothing to do with the course.

Speaking of course work, I finalized and submitted my learning journal entries. On one of them, I had originally planned to define thirteen words (the assignment said to define at least three), but I ended up cutting three of them out of the final draft. Both journal entries asked for information about me personally, instead of information about the topic of the course.

POLS 1503: Globalization
UNIV 1001: Online Education Strategies

It seems that our mother is registering Vanessa at the local high school. Is Vanessa not coming with us when we move? Our mother's threatened to leave Vanessa here before, so I can't be sure. Hopefully, our mother just plans to have Vanessa attend the local school until we find our new home, then have Vanessa transfer.

*EDIT Day 00652: Sunday, 2016 December 18*: I've moved "learning journal" content to a separate page now, accessible from the coursework section of the website.

Document modifications

On 2017-11-02, this journal page was modified in order to redact the name of the university.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

My mobile computing is once again under my control.

Day 00551: Thursday, 2016 September 08

Current countdowns:

20 unfinished weblog entries in July
11 days until mobile voice/SMS service with my current carrier ends
41 days until mobile data service with my current carrier ends
38 days until my old domain registrar can no longer counter my charge dispute

Patreon support told me to reach them via another contact method; a form on another website, so I did, though I'm not sure why they have multiple methods of contacting support if they don't all actually lead to people that can resolve issues.

Several months ago, you changed your CloudFlare settings, and I haven't been able to log in since. This is a combination of two problems. First, your log in form requires JavaScipt. It should be possible to log in with a simple HTTP POST request. Second, your JavaScript is behind a *SECOND* CloudFlare CAPTCHA wall due to being at a separate domain. This means that when I fill out the CAPTCHA to reach the log in page, I can't load the JavaScript. This second CAPTCHA never loads for me, because it's blocking the JavaScript file instead of a regular Web page. With the JavaScript file unable to load and the log in form refusing to allow log ins without JavaScript, I can't log in at all.

I complained about this issue in March and you still haven't fixed this. I am a paying customer. Please fix your log in page, CAPTCHA walls, and/or JavaScript so I can actually log in and get what I'm paying for.

The next time that I saw my email inbox, I'd received a letter from them.

Hey there!

Community Happiness Team here, eager to help you out!

For security purposes, we aren't able to manually reset a user's password, but if you know the email you used when you created your account, you can reset your password using the "forgot password" link from the log-in menu. If you previously requested your account be deactivated, you will not be able to log back into your old account and will need to create a new one.

If you have other questions related to logging in, you may find an answer in our Help Center. Let us know if you find what you are looking for; otherwise, we'll be in touch very soon!

Love,
Your Community Happiness Team

At first, I mistook this for an actual response from a Patreon employee instead of what it really was: the ramblings of an automated mailer robot. In frustration, I replied.

My password isn't the issue. I have my password. The issue is that you're JavaScript-based log in form is keeping its JavaScript file behind a CAPTCHA wall that never displays to the user.

Eventually, a live person got back to me, so I responded.

Michael from Patreon, Sep 8, 1:20 PM PDT

Hi There,

Thanks for reaching out to let us know there is a problem. I'm happy to pass this along to our engineering team, but don't seem to be able to find an account with this email address- would you mind letting me know the email address that's attached to your Patreon account?

I don't want to set the wrong expectations either- from my understanding this isn't something that we'd want to change, at least as part of our security protocols, and that javascript would be necessary for the login procedure. Again, I'm happy to pass this on to our engineers in case I'm off base and this is something we want to change and needs addressing- but I know it's difficult for us for any kind of follow up without your account info.

Let me know and we can peek into it.

best,

-Michael

Sorry about that, it's my spam trap email address. That way, I know exactly who is emailing me. My Patreon account email address is:

[REDACTED]

Let me be a bit more clear though. When I registered with Patreon, this wasn't an issue. Now, I can't even log into my account, either to get what I'm paying for or to cancel my subscription. It is absolutely mandatory that you either fix this problem, so I can continue using the Patreon content subscription that I'm paying for, or cancel my account, so I am no longer paying for what you won't allow me to access.

I would prefer that you fix the bug on your end, but if you won't do that, you at the very least need to stop charging me.

~ Yst Dawson

In POLS 1503, I'm once again having troubles getting this week's video to function. It seemed to work at first aside from the sound being way too low (my system sound is plenty high, which I verified by playing a local audio file). However, I paused the video for a couple minutes, after which the video would no longer play. This sucks. I don't know what's wrong with that video site, but it has issues. Unlike last week's readings, this week's readings are behine University of [REDACTED]'s login wall. If you're following along with my courses, I apologize for the inconvenience.

Unfortunately, I had a bad headache for much of the day. Until near the end of the day, I couldn't figure out why I had the headache, but now, I think that it had to do with the fact that it was hotter today than it had been. I couldn't concentrate much, so I tried to move on to another assignment.

Taking a look at my assignments in UNIV 1001, I found that I've got to write a paper, and this paper *must* be formatted using a particular proprietary font. Being a proprietary font, I of course don't have it installed, so this might be a bit tricky. I'll tell LibreOffice Writer to use that font, but since it's not present, it'll fall back to an existing font. Will it put instructions to use the required font in the file or will it put instructions to use the font that it fell back to in the file? It appears to be the former, but I can't be sure.

It turns out that my mother didn't get that job in Hollie. They also said that the interview today in Harrisburg didn't go as well as yesterdays. This isn't good. I'm not sure what, if anything, I can do to help the situation.

I found a new solution to our Internet connectivity situation. I hate having these stupid, untrustworthy, restrictive, nonfree firmwares installed on my Replicant device. I have three nonfree devices that I don't care about, but they two don't have the hotspot capability and the third has only a locked-down version of the feature. However, I found information suggesting that devices that appear to lack hotspot functionality sometimes actually do have it; they just lack the interface components needed to activate it. I found an application that controls the existing functionality, though it's unfortunately proprietary. The device that I want to run it on is already too restricted to be freed though, so it really doesn't matter except on principle. I installed it on the device that I like least (one that doesn't allow one to disable Google Play Services, causing constant errors as Google Play Services expects certain disabled components to not be disabled), and it works! I disabled every application that I could, regardless of if it was actually a threat, and now this think is pretty much just a hotspot. My mobile is no longer burdened by that task!

Unfortunately, the hotspot application is a bit incomplete. It doesn't offer the option to set up an open hotspot, so I simply set the name of the hotspot to The password is "password". and the password to password. My mother saw the network name as I was setting up their computer to use the new access point, and got confused as to how their computer was able to tell them the password before I'd entered it. I tried to explain, but they claimed that what I was saying didn't make sense. When they explained what they thought didn't make sense, it turned out they hadn't listened to me at all. I walked them through it more slowly, and they got frustrated. Now they're worried that my father will use my Wi-Fi access point. First of all, why does my mother care? I'm the one paying the bill on this access point, not my mother. Second, my father already has their own Wi-Fi network. Why would they use mine? Third, even if they did for some reason start using my access point, they'd quickly see how slow it is and switch back to their own access point. Seriously, my carrier is slowing my Internet speeds to a crawl because of how much data transfer we've used.

I decided that the safest way to be sure that the proprietary firmware was removed from my Replicant device was to completely reinstall Replicant. I couldn't do that from a ZIP file in the internal memory, as that was encrypted, so I tried insteas to use adb sideload. That didn't work though. Nothing was showing up on ClockworkMod's and and ADB was throwing an error. I happened to try to look at files on my external SD card though, and much to my surprise, ClockworkMod could read them! Last time that I tried something like that, ClockworkMod wasn't even able to mount the Ext4 file system. With this new ClockworkMod capability available, I rebooted into Replicant, transfered the ZIP file to the SD card via MTP, rebooted back into ClockworkMod, and installed the system without further issue.

Document modifications

On 2017-11-02, this journal page was modified in order to redact the name of the university.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Another study day lost

Day 00552: Friday, 2016 September 09

Current countdowns:

20 unfinished weblog entries in July
10 days until mobile voice/SMS service with my current carrier ends
40 days until mobile data service with my current carrier ends
37 days until my old domain registrar can no longer counter my charge dispute

I woke up this morning and I knew what my paper topic for UNIV 1001 needs to be: free software business models! The assignment requirements state that I must choose a topic that relates to my area of study or professional field. Software business models of any type should fit this requirement, but this topic also allows me to do two other things. First and foremost, this gives me an excuse and a chance to research free software business models. In all honesty, I'd love to get into software development, but I refuse to lock down my source code and take away the freedom of others. If this research goes well, it might give me some ideas as to how to make a free software business model work for me. Second, this topic will result in a paper that's actually worth having. I'm going to save any papers that I write for school and keep them here on my website, so having at least some of those papers express ideas that I actually want to convey will be nice. My other paper for the week is a bit political, which could play to my advantage as well. This second paper assignment is to write about an incident in which the World Bank or the International Monetary Fund messed up, then explain why I do or do not think that the organization in question can consistently provide assistance in an objective, unbiased and responsible manner. There's more to that paper of course, but it all boils down to if these organizations should be kept and how they should be reformed if they are. It's not exactly the direction that I'd normally head in my written work, but I might be able to convince people to see things my way. I can try to improve the world, even if only slightly.

I tried the proprietary Wi-Fi hotspot configuration interface application on my two other locked-down devices. It worked on one, but not the other. Much to my surprise, the one that worked wasn't the one that I expected to work. One of the devices lacks a hotspot configuration option in the main interface, so I figured that this application should work. It didn't. The other device has a built-in hotspot option available and visible, but it's locked down. The device checks with the original carrier, and if you're one their most expensive or least expensive plan (or ostensibly if you're using another carrier), the device won't activate the hotspot. I assumed that the hotspot configuration application would fail, as the hotspot feature would still refuse to activate based on my plan. However, it seems that it isn't the hotspot feature itself that's locked down, it's only the interface needed to turn it on! The application works as well as it did on the device that I configured with it yesterday.

Speaking of the mobile that I set up as a hotspot yesterday, it's started malfunctioning on me. Though it still showed that cell service was available, it wouldn't actually transmit any data over it. Neither machines connected to the hotspot nor the applications on the device itself could get any messages through. I thought that my carrier had cut the connection due to finding out that I was tethering against their policies, but the SIM card still worked on the other device that I got turned into a hotspot this morning. Having this other device take over the hotspot duties gave me time to debug later when my mother was away and unable to use the connection anyway. My guess is that some application that I disabled was necessary for cell communication. I didn't have time to test and see exactly which application was necessary, but I performed a factory reset (re-enabling all disabled applications), then disabled every application that both the device would allow me to disable and that had an actual application name (and not just a package name). SO far, the device seems to be functional again, though when I get a chance, I should maybe try disabling some of the nameless applications and see which ones aren't needed.

My mother is complaining about how slow the Internet connection is over my mobile. I know that it's bad, but it's better than they'd have without my help, right? I'm doing the best that I can. What more do they want me to do? We don't have the money for a real Internet connection, not to mention that they're not the one paying for this connection. I can only do what is in my power to do.

Trying to see if my new T-Mobile plan that I'll activate in forty days will include enough high-speed Internet access, I tried to check on the amount of data transfer that we've used this month. Unfortunately, that option no longer seems to be available in the Cricket Web interface. I did, however, see that Cricket has a new plan available for ten dollars less than my current plan. The catch is that this plan doesn't qualify for the automatic payments discount, so it'd only save me five dollars each moth. That puts that plan at the same price as the T-Mobile plan that I'm switching to, but with only a fifth of the high-speed data transfer per month. Obviously, I'm still switching service providers. As an experiment though, seeing as my high-speed data transfer for the month has already been exhausted for the month, I tried downgrading my plan. Instead of applying the change to next month, they applied it right away, resulting in an "overpayment" on my part. They prorated this month's service, and credited me $3.67 USD to my account. Seeing as I'm not continuing service with them, they now technically own me this money, though they're not going to hand it over. Considering the fact that we've already used up all of the high-speed data transfer of the higher plan though, I was going to let it slide. After all, downgrading th eplan had changed nothing for us, or so I thought.

After a bit, I realized the foolishness of my plan-switching. Next month, due to a strange configuration on Cricket's part, I'm going to get a full month of extra data transfer, assuming that they haven't fixed their system in the last year and a half. As I'm not getting that money back, I might as well make tha last payed month of service use the original plan, as that would allow us to have an extra gigabyte and a half of high-speed data transfer during the gratis month of service. Cricket hadn't updated my high-speed data connection usage bar on the Web interface, so it looked like they were still keeping track of the two and a half gigabytes of high-speed data transfer that we'd used, but when I went back to set the plan back to how I'd had it before, I saw that they'd completely reset my data connection usage bar. Not only were they crediting my account, they were giving me more high-speed data transfer allowance!

Apparently, my mother's interview yesterday in Harrisburg was a sham. They already knew who they were going to hire before they even held interviews. Unfortunately, due to red tape regulations, they're required to hold interviews before finalizing their decision, so like several other schools have done, they wasted the time of interviewees that were never candidates, getting their hopes up for nothing. Now my mother is ticked off and is lashing out at Vanessa, Cyrus, and I.

Our mother is now blaming Vanessa for their lack of a job. They say that if Vanessa had spoken up and admitted that they'd wanted to stay in Coos Bay, out mother wouldn't have quit their job and they'd still be employed. We wouldn't be living in the house that we're trying to sell, so we could get that cleaned up properly, and we'd have it on the market to sell by now. However, it was never Vanessa that said anything about wanting to leave Coos Bay. Our mother quit their job because it was our mother that was miserable. It took them seven years to find a stable job, but they threw that away because working in that school was an awful experience. Somehow, they thought that this time, it'd take less time to find a teaching job this time and that they'd be able to find their new job over the summer. Vanessa didn't speak up, true, but that only means that Vanessa didn't stand in the way of their decision to quit. Vanessa didn't want our mother to be stuck in a miserable job. To be clear, I I don't blame our mother for quiting their job, but in the end, it was their decision, not Vanessa's. To blame Vanessa is to demand that Vanessa be able to see the future.

Our mother also freaked out at Cyrus, and I, complaining that our bedroom was cluttered. Of course it's cluttered. We're storing sorted items here (mostly boxes, but also a large pile of blankets) that we don't have space elsewhere in the house. Are they our items? No! Is there anywhere better to put them? No! Cyrus and I spent a good portion of the day moving these items out of the bedroom, but it was quite counterproductive. We've had to mix these items with items in a couple of other stacks in the house, undoing the fruits of our sorting efforts. This is just idiotic.

While I was moving things out of the bedroom, I also did a bit of sorting of my own stuff. I've gotten rid of more items that I didn't want to part with in hopes of both becoming more mobile and giving our mother less reason to be on our case. For the record, this is the third iteration of my reduction of stuff, and I don't have much more that I can give up.

I threw out the packaging and "terms and conditions" booklets for my mobiles, but kept the instruction manuals for now. The boxes are protective, but they also take up a lot of space. I also got rid of four of my desktop machine hard drives, keeping only four. One of these four is broken, but I don't know which. I'm almost certain that the other three hard drives function. Once we're in a more stable situation with an actual Internet connection, I should be able to test them better. Likewise, I've gotten rid of all of my desktop machine RAM. The RAM could come in handy, but there's not much that I have left to part with, so it's got to go. Also while going through stuff, much to my horror, I found that my server is missing its Wi-Fi card. When I moved the Wi-Fi card from my mother's old machine to their new machine, it wasn't my mother's old machine! It was *my server*!! I now don't have a Wi-Fi card for my server. This isn't good, and I'm not sure how to get the Wi-Fi card back now that my mother's dependent on it. I'm almost certain that I'll need it back if and when we get a home network set up at our new home.

Our mother is enrolling Vanessa in an online high school, despite the fact that Vanessa wants to attend a brick and mortar school and see actual people in person. At first, I thought that our mother didn't have Vanessa's best interests at heart, but upon hearing more of the story, I understood the problem. It's a fact that our mother can be vindictive at times, but so can our father. If our father found out that we were moving after enrolling Vanessa in the local high school, our father might take our mother to court to try to get Vanessa to not have to transfer to another school mid-year. This could happen whether Vanessa wanted it to or not. The schools outside this city won't allow us to enroll Vanessa in their schools unless Vanessa has an address within their respective school districts, land lords won't allow us to rent from them unless we have income of at least three times their rental price, and my mother can't find a job with which to even get any income. With a local school out of the question and a not-yet-local school out of the question, an online school is the only available option.

Finally getting a chance to work on schoolwork, I made a list of all the readings for UNIV 1001. Last week, it was the POLS 1503 resources that were available to the public, but this week, it's UNIV 1001's resources. I have not finished reading all the study resources yet, but I'd better finish reading tomorrow. I wasn't productive yesterday due to my headache and I wasn't productive today due to my mother's freaking out. I've lost two of my five days for the week and I can't afford to lose much more time.

Google Books
Directory of Open Access Journals
Comparison of e-book formats - Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia
American Memory from the Library of Congress - Home Page
Purdue OWL: APA Formatting and Style Guide
Purdue OWL: APA Formatting and Style Guide
Google Scholar
How to Read a Journal Article
Reading, Writing, and Researching for History: A Guide for College Students
Reading, Writing, and Researching for History: A Guide for College Students
Anatomy of a Scholarly Article: NCSU Libraries
FAQ - Plagiarism.org - Best Practices for Ensuring Originality in Written Work
Academic Misconduct: Cheating, Plagiarism, and Other Forms | GSI Teaching & Resource Center
Home - Evaluating resources - Library Guides at UC Berkeley
Browse By Language: English - Project Gutenberg
2015-16 University of the People Catalog FINAL - university_catalog.pdf

Having documented the obstacles of the day here, I'm going to get back to studying. There's not enough time in the day to get much done, but I'll continue the readings to lesson how much I need to get done tomorrow.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Is FreedomPop a viable option?

Day 00554: Sunday, 2016 September 11

Current countdowns:

20 unfinished weblog entries in July
8 days until mobile voice/SMS service with my current carrier ends
38 days until mobile data service with my current carrier ends
3 days until my FreedomPop (no voice/SMS) cycle restarts and I can find out if I have a higher data-transfer limit than before
9 more FreedomPop friends until I hit my friend bonus limit
35 days until my old domain registrar can no longer counter my charge dispute

I had a strange dream last night. First, I awoke (in the dream) to find that my mother wouldn't leave my bedroom, so I couldn't get out of bed and get dressed. Once they finally left, I realized that what little had remained in bedroom before I'd gone to sleep was missing; Cyrus and our mother had moved it out before I'd woken up. We had a huge moving truck outside, and much of it had been packed! I went searching for the dresser that had been in my bedroom previously, as it contained (even in the real world) items that I didn't want packed up just yet. I woke up before ever finding where the dresser was (it was decidedly not in the moving truck), but while I was searching the house for it (the house's layout wasn't the same as the actual house that I'm in), I ran into someone that had been cryogenicly frozen, then later re-awoken. Apparently, they had specified that the people freezing them were to awaken them not more than three years later, but it had been over three years (the person didn't say how long, only that they were supposed to have been woken not more than three years from the time that they went under), and the person was frantic and ticked off about it. I had to continue my search for the dresser, as I had no way to help the thawed person, but as I left them, another version of me from the future arrived to help them out. Apparently, I was to gain time travel abilities in the future, and when I did, I came back to bring this person back to the past that they had tried to arrive in. They thought that help had arrived for them quickly, but that version of me explained that it'd actually arrived quited slowly. From the thawed person's perspective, help had arrived within the day that they'd woken up, but to future me, it had been years before I had the power to help them. I woke up in reality before anything happened with the time traveler and the thawed person. What a strange dream ...

I've changed Cricket plans again, and once more, Cricket has reset my high-speed data usage for the month. This will be the last time that I do this. The first time, I downgraded to the new $30 USD plan to see how that would work. Would the plan be switched mid-month, or would the plan be changed in the next billing cycle? As it turned out, they switched my plan right away, mid-month, both prorating the service bill (causing them to add a bill credit to my account) and reset my high-speed data allowance. Soon after this, I realized how foolish it was to switch plans during my final paid month, but as they'd reset the data usage allowance, I left the change in place. Today, I've switched back to the plan that I've already paid for (they simply took back most of the bill credit, which they won't pay back to me in cash anyway), so that the month after my final paid month will have a bit more high-speed data to use. It was never my intention to flip back and forth repeatedly between these plans and exploit their high-speed data allowance bug.

A while ago, I bought a FreedomPop SIM card. FreedomPop failed to make it clear to me that the voice service and "SMS" weren't regular voice service and real SMS messaging until after I'd paid for the SIM card and it was too late. Today, I saw an advertisement for FreedomPop saying that the gratis plan offers 500 megabytes of data transfer each month. Now that I don't need a telephone line, I thought that maybe this would be a great plan for me after all. I'm pretty short on funds, so if I use orWall to restrict data usage and only allow K-9 to get through, I should be able to keep my data usage under that. I might even have data transfer to spare for calendar and contact syncing (if I ever have a home Internet connection again)! Even if not, syncing might be possible ove USB somehow. Syncing is less urgent than email delivery. It would be nice for now to be able to use my mobile again, though even once we no longer need my main SIM card for our home Internet connection, I might just try sticking with this more restrictive data usage pattern and cancel my paid account. I logged into my FreedomPop account though and found that my account only offers 200 megabytes of data instead of the advertised 500 megabytes. My guess (and hope) is that I simply ordered the SIM card, then they later upped their offer. If that's the case, it wouldn't be them engaging in false advertising, but simply bad timing on my part. When the billing cycle ends, I might get the full 500 megabytes or I might be stuck on the 200 megabytes plan.

Looking for a way to make sure that I didn't go over (as FreedomPop *does* have overage charges instead of cutting you off properly), I found in the FreedomPop interface that if you add friends to your account, you get more data transfer each month. Odd. These friends need to be on FreedomPop, but are not required to be new customers and there doesn't seem to be any repercussions (such as shared data pools) for sending friend requests to people that you don't know. If I can get at least ten "friends" on FreedomPop, I'll hit their extra data transfer allowance cap of 500 megabytes. I've sent friend requests to sixty-four random people, people that have posted their email addresses online solely for the purpose of trying to get FreedomPop friend requests. If enough people go for it, I might have enough data transfer allowance to be fairly comfortable. So far, one person has accepted my friend request. 200 megabytes might honestly be enough, but not when you take into account that there could be accidental overages and the fees associated with them. I need some sort of safety buffer. Needless to say, I've set Replicant to cut me off before I hit that limit, though carrier usage isn't as accurate as the mobile's own measurements, so overage fees are still possible. Setting up the APN was oddly simple. For reasons that I don't fully understand, perhaps because of the incomplete service (no voice/SMS), only one piece of information is needed to connect to the network. The rest of the APN settings can be left blank, aside from the APN name, but that's just used internally by the device as a label. If you're not on FreedomPop, you can also use my affiliate link to get a SIM card for a discounted price, and I think that it will automatically set both of our accounts up as friends, getting us each 50 megabytes more data connection service per month. If you're on FreedomPop, feel free to shoot me an email (my email address is on my contact page) and I'll either send you a friend request on FreedomPop or send you the email address that I use with my FreedomPop account so that you can send the friend request (your choice). Please note that I use a different email address with every service provider that I use, so the email address on my contact page won't work for friend requests.

I got tired of sifting away literally thousands of spam emails from my old inbox, so I ended up eventually just deleting every email in the box. I don't need any past emails, that account isn't used any more. What I need instead is access to incoming future emails for account password resets.

LibreOffice Writer is a bit of a pain. It's less of a pain than Microsoft Office in my opinion, but I feel that it tries to emulate some of its quirks, such as treating characters that I type as some sort of syntax that means that Writer should insert something other than what I typed. This was getting in my way yesterday, and I was having to go back and correct Writer's "corrections". Attempting to fix my capitalization and rearranging the letters of words that I typed incorrectly is one thing. I find it a bit disconcerting, because I fear that if it makes an incorrect replacement, I won't notice it. However, to date, I've never noticed Writer making an incorrect replacement of that type. The killer, for me, is when LibreOffice Writer interprets my punctuation to actually mean something other than its literal self. For goodness sake, Writer is a document-producing application, not a markup interpreter! I kind of get it when Writer detects my URIs and converts them into hyperlinks. I always go back and undo that, but I get why it would do that. When I type a dash character through, I expect it to remain as I typed it, not convert itself into a different type of dash character once I've completed the next word. The dash doesn't even do it right away, it waits until I've typed a space, then a word, then another space. Yesterday, when I wrote the rough draft of my paper on free software business models, I wrote the first paragraph in Writer, then moved it to Geany before completing the rest, just to avoid these stupid automatic changes that I didn't want. I didn't want to have to scour the paper after finishing it to see what had been altered and what hadn't. This was an inelegant solution though. Believe me, I prefer working in plain text much more than working with a formatted document, but when the final product is to be a formatted document (as that's what the assignment called for), it'd be nice to be able to see the file in that format from the start. I asked for help in a LibreOffice support channel, fearing the worst. Most likely, or so I thought, this was a feature of LibreOffice that couldn't be turned off. After all, who would want to turn it off? Shouldn't documents be formated in a more "lovely" way? Such formatting would make it a bit of a pain when I reformat the essay for use on the Web though. When I turn it it, I plan to also make it available on my website. As it turns out though, there is a very simple solution. Under "Tools" => "AutoCorrect Options..." => "Options", there is a series of autocorrect cases that can be turned on or off. Perfect! I left some of them in place just because I'm poor at spelling (I'm a tactile learner), but I turned off most of the annoying ones. Today, for me, LibreOffice Writer has become a functional document-authoring application.

With LibreOffice writer no longer being a pain, I wrote up another draft of my UNIV 1001 essay, adding more details. Tomorrow, I really need to complete my POLS 1503 readings, then begin to draft that essay as well. I've focused too much on my UNIV 1001 essay, and am running out of time.

Enom wrote back and told me to go to their abuse form and file a complaint there. This is the second time that they've shipped me to another form to restate what the problem is. I don't have time to deal with this now, I'll get back to it at some point.

After using FreedomPop for the day, I found that my data connection usage rate was too high. K-9 isn't using a ton of bandwidth, but Orbot is. In fact, I think that Orbot might be the biggest user of the data connection that there is on my device. Even when the Tor network connection isn't in active use, Orbot must maintain it, which requires active outgoing network connections to the Tor nodes. I'm not yet sure how to remedy this. Also, I found that FreedomPop has taken the liberty of subscribing me to a paid add-on, and if I hadn't noticed, I'd have been charged $8 USD for it every month! Not cool. It's one thing to recommend addons, it's another thing to silently subscribe a user to them without their consent or knowledge. Just on principle, this makes me not want to give FreedomPop any money, even once I can afford to. This unofficial FreedomPop guide was what alerted me to the eight dollar service that FreedomPop was going to charge me for, and also alerted me to the fact that they expire account credits after thirty days. What the heck? Add that to their stupid enabled-by-default account top-off feature, which activated 100 megabytes to early, and you have an issue. I'm considering paying the five dollar fee to have automatic top-offs disabled, though I'll hold off for today. After having disabled the paid services that they had automatically subscribed me to, the links to the billing settings disappeared on me. Luckily, I still had the URI in my browsing history, but via normal navigation of the website, these settings were no longer available, making it impossible to disable automatic top-offs. I am not amused. I'll keep the link here in my journal, both in case someone else is looking for it and so that I can find the page myself when it comes time to pay to disable that antifeature. I should wait to disable it though. For one thing, I need to see if my plan's limitations will increase at the end of the month or if increasing the limitations requires a new SIM card altogether. For another, I should be ready to make use of the five dollar credit applied to my account when I pay to shut the top-off functionality off, so this should happen *after* my Cricket account with unlimited data has expired and *after* I've activated and used my T-Mobile SIM card and account credit. The T-Mobile SIM card and account credit will expire soon, so I don't have a whole lot of time left. After all, I bought that service and SIM card over two years ago! Only when I have no other data plans on the back burner should I finish dealing with my FreedomPop account.

Perhaps I'm being a bit hard on FreedomPop. Their tactics are a bit underhanded, but what do you expect from a company offering gratis mobile service? How in the world are they paying for this? Once I have my account set up the way that I like it, they won't be seeing much in the way of funds from me. After all, their prices are inflated to cover the cost of all of the people with gratis plans that they're servicing. In all honesty, it's the fact that they aren't upfront with their practices that's the issue, not the fact that it's not 100% gratis by default.

My mother applied for jobs in Turner, Salem, Sweethome, and Bethel today. They'll head over to Salem tomorrow with Vanessa to look for a new home to move into. I feel like all I can do is hope for the best.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Patreon continues to maliciously discriminate against Tor users

Day 00555: Monday, 2016 September 12

Current countdowns:

20 unfinished weblog entries in July
7 days until mobile voice/SMS service with my current carrier ends
37 days until mobile data service with my current carrier ends
2 days until my FreedomPop (no voice/SMS) cycle restarts and I can find out if I have a higher data-transfer limit than before
4 more FreedomPop friends until I hit my friend bonus limit
34 days until my old domain registrar can no longer counter my charge dispute

Patreon has written back, refusing to fix their bug. There's a way around it, of course, but it involves knowing how the Web works enough to find the loopholes. If it were just me, I'd probably do it, but I'm not the only Tor user. This needs to be repaired so that other Tor users have the same options available to them as everyone else does. If I were to use this loophole, it would diminish their incentive to fix their bug and would be paying them to maliciously discriminate against Tor users. It is worth losing access to these limited-time only albums to avoid funding a company that doesn't treat all Internet users as equal. Hoping to score the rare albums anyway, I contacted both Marc With a C and Professor Shyguy on the side to see if they'd offer me an alternative way to purchase their music given my situation. Marc said that they'd find a way for me if I really wanted them to, but that it would be a pain. That's fine. My goal isn't to impose, it's to fund an artist that releases free music. I'll just wait. Shyguy on the other hand, had a solution on their end. They told me to purchase Geekotica, a name-your-price album that even accepts $0, for the price of the the payment tier that I'm interested in, and include a note with the payment. Of course to decide what payment tier to use, my next question had to be about the license. I asked what license applied to these works, directly saying that I'f pay up to $30 USD per month if they were under a CC BY or CC BY-SA license. They didn't gve a direct answer, but did say this: @YstDo All my stuff, except the cover songs, are free to use on twitch, youtube, anywhere really.. That's good enough for me. I do wish that Shyguy would explicitly release under a free license, but a past conversation with them leads me to to believe that they don't understand how copyright works. Shyguy is an artist, not a lawyer. I don't think that there's any malicious intent here, and I don't foresee any problems as long as proper attribution is used.

The albums scored through this deal so far are The White Lie Album (an album that I previously discovered was nonfree), some random stuff that I have already (most of which is free), Fragmentation (an album that I own three copies of on Bandcamp, in addition to a physical CD of the album), "Aeronauts Tracks" (which don't bode well, as the Aeronauts wrote the nonfree The White Lie Album), and "game music". That game music should be where the interesting things are. I listened to one track, which was awesome, though I don't currently have time to listen to it all and/or sort it into groups based on whether it's known to be nonfree or if it's probably fine.

Speaking of having three virtual copies of Fragmentation on BandCamp, it seems that purchasing a second copy of Geekotica (as I'd bought that album in the past) didn't add a copy of it to my collection. This means that as I buy this album again and again each month, I'm not going to end up with a collection consisting mostly of copies of Geekotica. It seems that physical items count as separate from virtual items, as far as the collection is concerned. If the physical item corresponds to a virtual item, it allows for another copy of that item to be in the collection, but otherwise, you only end up with at most one of each album.

I finished up the readings for POLS 1503, then began research for my POLS 1503 assignments. I really should have started sooner, and worked on them at the same time as my main UNIV 1001 assignment. My discussion assignment for UNIV 1001 also should have been completed on the first day, and I should put off my "journal" assignment for UNIV 1001 until I finish the all of the other assignments for the week. If I hope to be useful to the moving process, find employment, and do well in school all at once, I need to get better at time management. Research isn't going too well though. I'm finding a lot of information about how bad that the World Bank and International Monetary Fund are (which will be important for one assignment), but not much on a specific failed project (which I need for the other assignment). The World Bank has screwed up so many times and in all the same ways, so most sources just lump all of these incidents together.

Vanessa and our mother were unsuccessful in finding a home in Salem today. I'm not sure what the sense would be in moving though before my mother finds a job. If a job is found after we move and it's outside of the area that we've moved to, my mother might have to turn down the job if they've signed a lease agreement. From the sound of it too, everywhere that they've looked requires a one-year lease agreement when they even have openings.

Five more people on FreedomPop accepted my friend requests, so I now get 500 megabytes of data per month. Although, to be sure that I avoid overage fees, I can only use up to 350 megabytes of it.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Grading and submitting essays

Day 00564: Wednesday, 2016 September 21

Current countdowns:

20 unfinished weblog entries in July
28 days until mobile service ends and I renew on a tablet plan
26 days until my old domain registrar can no longer counter my charge dispute

I managed to get back into Google account using my mobile, which was logged in via GApps Browser, a Google Web applications sandbox. I'm still weary of Google, and it's only a matter of time before they freak out and lock down my account again, but as long as my mobile remains logged in, I might be able to reclaim my account. That said, when the first account got locked down, I *was* logged into the account on GApps Browser, yet I wasn't able to unlock it from within like I was this time. If the account ends up locked down that badly again or if I end up logged out on GApps Browser, I'll have no recourse.

My mother went to their interview in Sweet Home today. They said that it went okay, but not great. They have another interview in Salem on Tuesday though, so maybe that one will go better.

I graded all six papers today that I was required to grade this week. Technically, I'm a bit behind my desired schedule, but I got everything handed in by the deadline! The first essay seemed perfect. I felt odd giving a perfect score though. I mean, I want to give a perfect score to everyone, but will I be marked down for doing that? I feel like I'm more of a lenient grader than many people would be. The grading criteria is pretty specific, so it seems like it would be hardish to give the wrong score, but it also seems like because the grading criteria is so specific, it'd be hard to miss many points if you're actually trying. The second essay that I graded cleared that worry from my mind though. This essay in no way met the required standard. It didn't meet the minimum word count given to us before we wrote our own essays, nor did it even answer all of the questions posed by the assignment. The other four essays all did better than the second essay, but not as well as the first. I would prefer that everyone do well, but at least I won't be accused of giving only perfect scores, and I made very clear in my grading notes exactly why I gave the scores that I did. These essays were supposed to be anonymous to avoid favoritism, but Ola has a tag line with their name in it that thy include a the end of every post. They included it in their essay as well, along with a few other instances of their name! I'm not sure exactly what to think of it, but it's hilarious. After grading my assigned six papers from last week, I submitted both my EFF essay for POLS 1503 and my proctored exam essay for UNIV 1001.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.1 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

My mother got the job in Sweet Home!

Day 00565: Thursday, 2016 September 22

Current countdowns:

20 unfinished weblog entries in July
27 days until mobile service ends and I renew on a tablet plan
25 days until my old domain registrar can no longer counter my charge dispute

My mother got the job in Sweet Home! It seems that it's only a one-year job, but that there are new openings yearly. With their foot now in the door, my mother should be able to snag another job for next year if they decide that they want to stay. T-Mobile seems to mostly have coverage in the area based on their coverage map, but as Vanessa and our mother were headed out to register Vanessa for school and get our mother checked into their classroom, I sent my mobile with Vanessa to have them verify the coverage. Vanessa didn't listen to my instructions though, and instead of reporting if there was 2G, 3G, H, or H+ service and if there was any signal at all, instead reported a number of signal bars. In any case, there is signal in the area, so I can stick with T-Mobile this school year. Sweet Home is too small of a city to have a T-Mobile store though, which is a bit of a drag. It looks like I'll need to bike twelve miles to pay my bill, then bike twelve miles back. At least I'll only have to do that once every thirty days. A bigger issue weighs on my mind though. Will job opportunities be just as far away? Am I going to have to bike twenty-four miles every day? How will that effect my schoolwork?

Yesterday, I thought that Ola was silly, exposing their identity in their essay submission, which was theoretically supposed to be anonymous. Today though, I have to eat those words. I took a look at my assigned essay topic for this week, and now I'm going to have to expose who I am this week as well. One of the questions that I'm required to address is of how I will keep myself accountable, which I do through this public journal. To mention the journal but not mention where to find it seems like I'm trying to hide something but feign openness. That doesn't sound like holding myself accountable at all! Leaving out my URI isn't really an option, if you think about it.

Bandcamp sent me an email today, and they're now accepting credit cards directly instead of requiring use of PayPal. This is awesome news! I can finally be free of PayPal! Well, mostly. There is a catch. Bandcamp only accepts credit cards directly when ordering digital music. They still demand use of PayPal when the customer is ordering anything physical. I do prefer digital music though, so I only place orders for physical items from Bandcamp artists when there's more to the order than just a physical copy of what is offered for download after purchase.

I ended up taking a break again today. I should have started on my studies for the week, but today was a day of celebration and recuperation. Not knowing where I'm going to be in the coming months and not being able to job hunt has been a major stressor for me, and now, things are finally moving along; we're actually going somewhere.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Tablet activation issues

Day 00567: Saturday, 2016 September 24

Current countdowns:

20 unfinished weblog entries in July
25 days until mobile service ends and I renew on a tablet plan
23 days until my old domain registrar can no longer counter my charge dispute

I received an email addressed to my old recovered email account that told me the third and final domain that I'm being charged for on my old account with my previous domain registrar. It's one that I used for a domain hack email address! It was supposed to look professional, and I suppose that it does, but it's not a domain that I'd ever have remembered registering; that's why I could never guess it.

I went to the local T-Mobile store to verify that they couldn't offer me a prepaid tablet plan on my "smartphone" device. Last time, the representative that I talked to tried to set the plan up for me, but couldn't find prepaid tablet plans anywhere in the system. It seemed that the only prepaid plans that could be set up at that location were "smartphone" plans. To be clear, this was regardless of what device I brought, and had nothing to do with the classification of my device. The representative that I spoke to today kept pushing for me to switch to postpaid, saying that they couldn't add tablet plans to the account unless it was a postpaid account. That seemed to mean that the system was the same as before, so I continued on to somewhere that I knew sells prepaid T-Mobile tablet SIM cards. It turns out that they have two types of T-Mobile SIM cards there. One type is exclusively for "smartphone" plans while the other can be used for either "smartphone" plans or tablet plans. They have no tablet-only SIM cards, so it's odd that they have "smartphone"-only SIM cards. Unfortunately, the SIM card seems to be detecting that I'm on a "smartphone", and is refusing to activate using a tablet plan. I tried borrowing a tablet from a friend though, and the SIM card isn't accepting the tablet as a tablet either. Maybe the detection isn't what I think that it is. Additionally, T-Mobile's IMEI verification page doesn't seem to recognize the IMEI of the tablet or any of my"smartphone" devices.

I spoke with a support representative about it, and they kept insisting that tablet activation must be accomplished via a telephone call, which directly contradicts the instructions that came with the SIM card. I kept explaining that, but they wouldn't listen, continuing to insist that the only way to activate it was via telephone. Obviously, that isn't an option, and I eventually gave up, ended the live Web support chat, and started a new one with a new representative. This representative said that I could activate it through another webpage that they gave me a link to, but that page kept insisting that my email address and password combination were incorrect. I verified that they weren't by logging into another part of the website, and additionally be making sure that a different error message was present if I tried to use an unrecognized email address. I can't seem to get this SIM card to activate on a tablet plan, but it still does seem to accept "smartphone" plans. The worst-case scenario seems to be that I let my current service plan end, then activate the new SIM card on the same plan to make use of the account funds that came with it.

My reading assignment for today wasn't too long:

Microsoft Word - CHOICES OF SUCCESSFUL STUDENTS _2_.docx - successfulstudents.pdf
Intrinsic and Extrinsic Motivations: Classic Definitions and New Directions - Ryan,+Deci+00.pdf
5 Lifelong Learning Power Tips for the Serious Learner
Self Directed Learning: 15 Ways of the Successful Self-Directed Learner
Attention Required! | CloudFlare

After reading all of that, I wrote up most of my essay for the week, but I will need to sleep on the last paragraph and a half. The assignment says to include a word count, but doesn't tell what the minimum word count is. I should be above it though already with just what I've written today, before adding the final paragraph and a half. I'll be at over a thousand words by the time I'm through, and no assignment in this course has required that many words yet, but it would be nice to be sure that I've written enough.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Why does someone think that I'm a *parent*!?

Day 00568: Sunday, 2016 September 25

Current countdowns:

20 unfinished weblog entries in July
24 days until mobile service ends and I renew on a tablet plan
22 days until my old domain registrar can no longer counter my charge dispute

I received yet another email from dotMP today, this time warning me that I only have seven days before my accidentally-registered //ystyst.mp. domain expires. Once it expires, I might register a new domain elsewhere to use with a new job-related email address. The two names that I'm currently considering are both available. This time, I'll probably register under the //isla.pr. SLD. Registrations there are very inexpensive, though the "isla" part of the domain might look strange to people here in the States. The //pr. TLD might be of use though, as it is composed of my legal name's initials. Directly registering under this TLD is far too expensive though, which is why the third-level registration is more feasible.

I took the ungraded UNIV 1001 quiz that I forgot to take yesterday, then took a look at this week's POLS 1503 reading assignment. Unfortunately, it's hidden behind a login wall, so you can't take a look at it, but it's forty-nine pages long! This week's assigned video actually functioned though. I also completed the grading of all six of the peer essays I was assigned. I'll probably complete the reading assignment tomorrow, as I'll have the house to myself.

Someone put me on a list of parents on twitter. Why do they think that I would ever have children, let alone that I currently do? I've given no such signals. I would pass this off as someone not paying attention to who they stuck in groups and ignore it, but groups such as these are public. I find the thought of being labeled as a parent to be mildly offensive, so I looked up a way to degroup myself. As it turns out, it's not that hard, though the way to do it is a bit unintuitive. Strangely, Twitter doesn't offer a way to outright remove yourself from a group, but if you block the user that put you in said group, you'll automatically be removed from any group that they've put you in. The removal is permanent, so if you unblock them, you'll remain free of the group, though they will be able to put you back in.

Tomorrow will be Vanessa's first day of school and our mother's first day of work. Vanessa's vanessa two or three weeks late in attending school though, so hopefully there won't be too much make up work. Now Vanessa can start making new friends again!

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

T-Mobile support representatives appear to be incompetent.

Day 00569: Monday, 2016 September 26

Current countdowns:

20 unfinished weblog entries in July
23 days until mobile service ends and I renew on a tablet plan
21 days until my old domain registrar can no longer counter my charge dispute

By the end of the day, I'd spoken with a total of fourteen T-Mobile, including the representatives from yesterday. None of them were able to get my tablet line activated. In fact, one representative even made the problem *worse*! The representatives that I spoke with today were manning the T-Mobile support Twitter account, and while new representatives kept jumping in, they seemed to only pay attention to the last couple messages from me, not the whole conversation. I had to tell them *repeatedly* that activating the tablet over a telephone was in no way an option and that the instructions that came with the SIM card had promised the option to activate over the Web. The one representative even transfered my "smartphone" line to the new SIM card instead of activating the tablet line! Not only did this fail to put the account credit that I paid for with the SIM card on the account, causing a loss of $40 USD, it ended service on the original SIM card and left me with no SIM card to use for the tablet line. My best guess is that they read the last couple messages from me, but didn't read the full conversation that I'd been having with several representatives already. They partially reversed the process once I expressed my extreme displeasure, but now the SIM card looks borked. While it used to allow access to the tablet-activation page, though the page didn't seem to work, it now doesn't allow Internet access at all. Great. They may have killed the new SIM card and/or caused me to lose the $40 USD credit. Eventually, one of the representatives recommended trying to activate the SIM card in-person at a T-Mobile branch. They don't offer prepaid tablet plans, but the representative said that because I have a SIM card already, they might be able to set up the plan anyway. I'll walk in and try to get them to do that tomorrow.

I completed the forty-nine-page reading assignment, then took a test based on it. I didn't do as well on the test as I would have liked to, but I did alright.

It seems that the Samsung GT-i9100G finally made it back to the seller, as they've now issued me my refund. It would have been nice if they'd correctly labeled the device on the product page so I wouldn't have bought it and needed to send it back, but at least that problem is over.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.1 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

No telephone service required

Day 00570: Tuesday, 2016 September 27

Current countdowns:

20 unfinished weblog entries in July
20 days until my old domain registrar can no longer counter my charge dispute

At the T-Mobile store, I was informed that if I activate the SIM card in-person, I'll lose my $40 USD account credit due to the fact that the in-person activations don't use activation codes. Obviously that wasn't an option, so I headed home to argue with T-Mobile support some more. Before I began, I decided to put a little pressure in just the right place by publicly saying that I miss Cricket. Before I could even address my next message directly to T-Mobile support, they jumped on me, asking me to give them another chance! Dealing with five more support representatives, one was finally able to do their job and activate the tablet plan, no telephone required. I swear, there's always a way to do things without having telephone service. Anyone that tells you otherwise is a dirty, dirty liar. A telephone call would have saved me some time for sure, but the lost time was more than worth it just because of the principle. Unfortunately, it seems that my preferred tablet plan is only available if auto-pay is activated, but unlike telephone use, auto-pay is a burden that I'm willing to bear. T-Mobile support seems to be relieved that I gave them a chance after this morning's tweet. They don't understand that I had never given up on getting support. That well-worded tweet was to get their attention. It worked, and now, so does my data plan. During the activation-debugging process, the support representative temporarily activated "smartphone" service on the SIM card. I considered using it to activate another Google Voice account for later, but decided against it on the grounds that then Google would have my more current telephone number. As it turns out, that wouldn't have been the case though, as when the service was switched to tablet service, the number was changed. Also, I think that I now know why the tablet-activation website was rejecting my device and the tablet that I borrowed. Despite the representative activating the plan using the tablet's IMEI, the account shows my own device's model number. When I first accessed the activation website, or perhaps when I first allowed my device to access the T-Mobile towers using that SIM card, T-Mobile associated the SIM card with the mobile device and still hasn't let go of that, despite having later seen the SIM card in the tablet. If I want to activate a tablet plan next time, I can't allow the SIM card to be placed in my own device until *after* the plan has been activated in a tablet.

T-Mobile support was supposed to get back to me about the T-Mobile Tuesdays website issue, but they did not. I thought it best not to mention it to the support team though. I don't want to overload the support team and I don't want to seem ungrateful. No worries though, the gifts this week are pretty bad like last week's gifts. The four gifts are a ride in an ostensibly fossil fuel-burning car, a desert made from cow excretions, a subscription to an ostensibly proprietary magazine, ans a small discount on clothing. The last of these is the only one that I'd even consider using, but I get all of my clothing second hand. Second hand clothing is bound to be much less expensive than the clothing offered by the T-Mobile partner, even after the small discount.

Between the high level of stress today and the lack of time due to arguing with T-Mobile support representatives, I didn't do any schoolwork. With all of the kinks worked out of my tablet plan though, I should be much more able to focus on schoolwork tomorrow.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

The MetroPCS tablets are being phased out along with their data plans.

Day 00572: Thursday, 2016 September 29

Current countdowns:

20 unfinished weblog entries in July
18 days until my old domain registrar can no longer counter my charge dispute

I checked out the list of schoolwork that I have to get done this week, and it turns out that this is a slow week. Figuring that I had plenty of time, I took a trip down to the local MetroPCS store to ask them about their tablet. The problem is that I seem to keep moving to a new city every school year. I'm moving to Sweet Home this time, which is T-Mobile's coverage zone, but last year, I was in Coos Bay, where T-Mobile's towers don't yet reach. MetroPCS doesn't have a bring your own tablet option and I can't afford to buy a new MetroPCS tablet if I leave the T-Mobile service area before the tablet plan has saved me enough to pay for the tablet then move back into the T-Mobile coverage zone. With that in mind, I walked in and asked the representative if MetroPCS tablets can be *reactivated* if I leave the coverage zone and return. They explained that yes, the tablets can be reactivated on the MetroPCS tablet plan, but the tablets are no longer available in that particular store. Tablet sales have been too low because people have been buying large smartphone data packages that can cover their tablet usage, then getting their tablets elsewhere. I assume that the representative meant that these people are tethering the tablets, but I didn't ask. As MetroPCS doesn't offer the option to bring a good tablet, it makes sense that people wouldn't be interested in the tablet plan. When I asked where to find a store that did still has the tablets, the representative said that they might only be available online, so I explained that the MetroPCS website says that they're only available in-store. The representative concluded that MetroPCS is probably phasing out the tablets. While I don't like the thought of the tablets being phased out without a bring your own tablet plan being introduced, the evidence that I have does back that up. The MetroPCS tablet is no longer findable on the website via internal links. One must pull out a search engine to find that page, as it still exists and never got deindexed. Additionally, the tablet *plan* pages no longer exist on the website. Any links to them result in a redirect to the smartphone plan page. The representative speculated that there might be a bring your own tablet plan in the future, but with the plan information pages having been removed, this seems unlikely. These tablets will be even harder to get in three months when my T-Mobile service that I've already paid for ends, so getting a tablet later seems unlikely. I could try to find a used tablet, but that comes with two problems. First, as I'm not the original owner, I can't request that it be unlocked. I'd need to make sure that the original owner unlocked the tablet before they sold it, and for some reason, I get the feeling that a lot of people don't unlock their devices, especially low-end devices such as these. Second, if the IMEI switch doesn't bring the plan to the device that I actually want it on, I can't exactly return the tablet if I didn't get it directly from MetroPCS. I'm not seeing this tablet plan as feasible, so it looks like I won't be getting a tablet for a great while. Finances are tight, so a tablet that doesn't save me money (or at least not cost anything) is out of the question.

Once I got back home, I started working on the journal assignments that I was supposed to have done yesterday, but that weren't technically due until today. In the first one, I was supposed to choose an area of technological advancement that's moving globalization along. With mobile devices on my mind, I started writing about them. In many third-world countries, they are the only access that the people have to the Internet.

One area of technological advancement that's had a huge impact on globalization is mobile communication technologies. In some developing countries, Internet access is primarily only available through mobile devices (The Levin Institute, n.d.). While many people consider mobile devices to be telephones, many are in fact not telephones at all. Anything labeled as a "smartphone" is actually a pocket-sized computer (Williams, 2010). With theses computers and the towers needed to connect them to the Internet popping up in third-world countries, the owners of these devices are able to get much closer to the modern age and access the online trove of information that the first world has been enjoying for quite a while.

Not everyone is using these cellular service to its full potential. In Africa, the main usage of mobile devices is basic SMS (Pew Research Center, 2015). In fact, most of the mobile devices in Africa aren't computers, but actual telephones (so-called "dumb phones". However, this still helps Africans stay in touch with those that they care about. Having towers in the area also allows those that do want to reach out globally to do so by investing in pocket-sized computers.

[I can't finish this without endorsing actual telephone service and telephone numbers. I'll have to scrap this and find another topic.]

References:

The Levin Institute. (n.d.). Microsoft Word - tech2011 - glob101techandglob.pdf. Retrieved from http://my.uopeople.edu/pluginfile.php/126112/mod_book/chapter/94453/glob101techandglob.pdf

Williams, A. (2010, January 7). "Smart Phone" is a Misnomer: It's a Computer, not a Phone - ReadWrite. Retrieved from http://readwrite.com./2010/01/07/smart-phones-smart-phones-all/

That didn't go well though, as I quickly learned that the devices aren't the pocket computers that people here in the United States usually have. Instead, they are *actual telephones* that just happen to be portable. My only two options if I continued on that topic were to either paint the telephone system (and therefore, the telephone number system) in a positive light or paint being able to keep connected with one another in a negative light. These pocket telephones are no doubt a step up from not being connected at all, I won't argue against that. However, I refuse to say anything positive about the awful system that is telephony. It's like saying that use of a ferry is a step up from using a raft fashioned from ropes and branches. That's technically very true, but when bridge technology has existed for quite a while, ferries are really nothing to brag about and nothing to hold in high regard. My next attempt at that assignment involved discussing peer production. I'm not sure how much it really is a technological advancement, so I'm not sure how much it fits the assignment, but it is treated as a technological innovation in last week's readings and it certainly has impacted globalization. I also bundled open source software (not to be confused with free software), as that was another "innovation" mentioned in the readings, and the two go hand-in-hand quite nicely.

I didn't really run into problems big enough to warrant starting over on the second assignment that I needed to get turned in today, as it was mostly meant to be a self-reflection assignment.

POLS 1503: Globalization
UNIV 1001: Online Education Strategies

My mother needed to unwind a bit from their first week of work, so they came into my bedroom and discussed a few things with me. My mother doesn't seem to like their new workplace, and has come to the realization that they're really not as good of a teacher as they thought that they were. They're only getting hired by bad districts that good teachers won't touch. I was thinking the same thing before they landed this job to be honest. I mean, my mother can't even grasp simple concepts, can't keep causality straight, and doesn't even have basic computer skills, though computers have become an important part of modern teaching. I wasn't going to ever tell them what I thought because it wouldn't do any good. All it would do is hurt their feelings needlessly, but it seems that they understand now without my help even. Apparently, my mother forgot that this job is only until the end of the year too, and was re-informed that it was temporary. Now, they say that they wish that they'd known, and that had they known, they might not have accepted the job. I know for a fact that they *would* take the job even knowing that it's temporary, not only because I understand that our situation is desperate, but because they told me when they took the job that it was only until the end of the year. We're either moving again at the end of the school year or my mother's using this as a way to get their foot in the door and get another job there when the new openings are listed.

Cyrus and Vivian are coming over this weekend, apparently. I wonder how things are going with them.

Document modifications

*EDIT Day 00652: Sunday, 2016 December 18*: I've moved "learning journal" content to a separate page now, accessible from the coursework section of the website.

On 2018-01-16, my sister, Vivian, requested that I replace all instances of her legal name in my journal with the name "Vivian". She also asked that the name of the organisation she works for be redacted. This page was modified to fulfil that request.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.